Ben Butterworth <u>ben@orth.uk</u>

London, UK [Stack Overflow, LinkedIn, Website]

I've worked with a variety of platforms, runtimes and languages for library development, machine learning, parallel processing and app development. I've worked on mobile APIs and distributed systems as a Backend Engineer at Ocado.com, before I earnt my Computer Science degree. I achieved first-class honours, dean's list and distinction for degrees in computer science and engineering at Imperial College including time at MIT. I'm a decent communicator: writing documentation, hundreds of Stack Overflow answers (and questions Google-Poisson

WORK EXPERIENCE

SDK Developer at Ably.com (**Flutter**/ iOS/ Android)

April 2021-January 2022

- Oversee development by contractors working on other SDKs (iOS and Android)
- Added push notification and encryption support to <u>package</u>, abstracting iOS and Android APIs into ergonomic Flutter API. Spawning Flutter Engines for background processing.
- Added Swift Package Manager support to 1 Objective-C and 1 Swift library, while using advanced module structure to ensure proper API access control for SDK users.
- Found bugs in internal and open source code, providing actionable bug reports & fixes
- Built an anonymous video calling app (https://club2d.orth.uk) which generates a 3D face mesh, rendering it other user's browsers in real time. Gave talk at JSMonthly.
- Released open-source libraries: creating changelogs, writing documentation, handling issues and keeping enterprise customers such as banks feeling supported and happy.
- Fixing and enhancing documentation on the Ably documentation site covering all SDKs
- Contributed Flutter Engine PR to enhance Flutter plugin development on iOS.

Mobile ML Engineer at Popsa.com (Android, iOS, TensorFlow) Sep 2020 - April 2021

- Designed and built on-device photo library face recognition feature, including parallel image processing and IO, profiling and optimising memory and throughput across devices
- Built photo albums title suggestions using EXIF data, using Protocol-buffer based APIs.
- Wrote NumPy files parser in Kotlin to investigate cross platform image processing inconsistencies and subsequently discovering a bug in Android graphics library.
- Optimized models in Python with additional layers and pre-processing to improve performance
- Built internal tools for data scientists, including Python applications and macOS CLI tool to run models, including distribution for macOS (notarization) and progress animations.

Mobile Engineer, University software project (React Native)

Dec 2019 - May 2020

- Published mobile app to help 'calculate carbon impact of food' on Apple Store and Play Store.
- Wrote helpful documentation and automated processes with scripts and CI/CD tools.
- Built landing page in React and GatsbyJS in 4 hours: https://foodprint.orth.uk.

- Helped developers learn and be productive by teaching and guiding them, opting for Javascript and React Hooks for simplicity (Used Redux, Typescript in personal projects).
- Built navigation, GraphQL network requests, authentication with good test coverage, and assisted less experienced developers with NodeJS, Apollo Server and authentication.

Software Engineer (Mobile Team) at Ocado Technology (Java)

Feb - Sep 2019

- Designed mobile friendly APIs for API gateway microservice accessed by white-label mobile applications sold to international supermarkets (e.g. Bon Preu, Kroger).
- Reduced response time for requests by 3x, 1.24s to 0.39s by merging related APIs.
- Won weekly internal coding competition twice, involving 10-15 experienced developers.

EDUCATION

Imperial College, Master's in Computer Science, Distinction (highest)

Oct 2019 - Aug 2020

- C++, OOP, Computer vision, ML, Information Security, Networking and Distributed Systems.
- Thesis: comparing/ implementing real-time ML systems for the edge and in cloud.
- Built <u>receipt scanning and reimbursement app</u> with React Native as part of a team who focused
 on the backend implementation, then invited to present app and meet employees at <u>Fintech</u>
 <u>start-up</u> with ~£150m investment.

Imperial College, Master's in Engineering, 1st class (highest), Dean's list 2014 - 2018

- Developed automated painting machine, one component of an automated mini factory, using Autodesk SketchBook, Arduino, Solidworks, 3d printing, CNC machining
- Thesis: simulating and analysing nanoparticle behaviour in human cells using Python, Bash and molecular dynamics (GROMACS); and highest marks in simulation/ modelling.
- Business School courses: Project Management (A*) and Strategic Management (A*).

Massachusetts Institute of Technology, exchange student

2017

- Courses: Intro to Algorithms, Entrepreneurship in Engineering, Intro to Machine Learning.
- Research assistant: Analysed molecular simulation data for <u>publications</u> using Python.
- Photographer at student-led newspaper society.

Harrow School, A-levels: 4A* in Further Maths, Physics, Chemistry, Maths

2012 - 2014

- Several 100%'s in A-levels exams; Represented school in rifle shooting and football.
- Awarded gold prize in UK Chemistry Challenge and silver prize in Chemistry Olympiad.

VOLUNTEERING, HOBBIES & AWARDS

- Self-taught ML engineering and TensorFlow, achieving the <u>TensorFlow Developer Certificate</u>.
- Organising and running events for 800 students in Halls, given Imperial Volunteer award.
- Experience with DNS, Docker, NodeJS, NoSQL, MySQL, AWS, GCP, Terraform, Cloudflare.